Guide to the Sylvester Manor Archive 1649-1996 MSS.208
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Record Group IV: Horsford Family
  - Series A: Eben Norton Horsford
    - Subseries 11: Personal Papers and Poetry
      - German Wax Seals, undated, circa 1830 - 1893; cuid3487 (Box 90, Folder 72)
  - Series B: Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford
    Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford was born on September 26, 1824 to Samuel Smith Gardiner and Mary Catherine Gardiner. Mary was privately tutored on Shelter Island before attending the Albany Female Academy, where she met Eben Norton Horsford. Mary and Eben wed in 1847 and later produced four daughters: “Lilian” (Mary Leila Horsford Farlow), “Kate” (Mary Katherine Horsford), Gertrude Hubbard Horsford Fiske, and “Mamie” (Mary Gardiner Horsford Curtis). Mary was a poet and had several works published in local newspapers; her volume Indian Legends and Other Works was published in 1855. Mary passed away on November 25, 1855, only months after Mamie was born.
    Record Group IV, Series B, pertains to Mary L’Hommedieu Horsford’s personal and public life in the form of two series arranged by genre. Series 1: Correspondence includes communication in the form of invitations and letters. Series 2: Manuscripts and Printed Materials consists of private and professional documentation in the form of diary entries, collected and original poetry by Mary and others, records of Mary’s writing process in the form of manuscripts, printing proofs, and typescripts of her work Indian Legends and Other Poems. Series 2 also includes ephemera and printed materials in the form of a personal bible full of marginalia; Jared Bell Waterbury’s Advice to a Young Christian on the Importance of Aiming at an Elevated Standard of Piety (1830) was once a part of this series, but it has been removed to the Fales Special Collections and cataloged. Please search Bobcat to locate this work.
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      Record Group IV, Series B, Subseries 1, pertains to Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford’s personal and public life in the form of communication with her family, friends, and members of her local community. Genres range from contact in the form of invitations, letters, and collected and original poetry.
      Series D, Subseries 1, is dominated by records that capture Mary’s personal life through conversations with her family and friends. Subjects range from current community events, private family business and Shelter Island estate management, to public and shared social experiences, testimonies of religious faith, to travel. This subseries features seventy-seven letters (281 pages) from “A.D.W.” or “Cousin Abby,” (possibly Abby Dwight Woodbridge), in which Abby shares her love of poetry with Mary.
      Personal correspondence.; Personal papers.; Poetry.; Printed ephemera.; Invitations.; Notes.; Letters (correspondence); Botta, Anne C. Lynch (Anne Charlotte Lynch), 1815-1891
      - “Ana”: Providence, RI, 1843 April 2; cuid3488 (Box 91, Folder 1)
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], Albany, NY”
        Sent From: “Ana”
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social; Cousin Emma, Mrs. Pomeroy, Professor Eben Norton Horsford
      - Chapel, Grace: Sag Harbor, NY, [no year] August 12, circa 1830s; cuid3489 (Box 91, Folder 2)
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary L'H [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], ℅ Miss Anne [Charlotte] Lynch [Botta], Providence, RI”
        Sent From: “Grace Chapel”
      - "Cherie": [New York, NY], undated, circa 1830s; cuid3490 (Box 91, Folder 3)
        Addressed To: “Miss Gardiner,” [Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        Sent From: “Cherie,” [Unidentified Location, Possibly New York, NY]
        Measurements: 4.25” x 5.25”
      - "Cousin Helen": [New York, NY], 1843 March 28; [no year] July 22; undated, circa 1840s; cuid3491 (Box 91, Folder 4)
        Sent From: “Cousin Helen,” “Helen E.P.,” [Unidentified Location, Possibly New York, NY]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; Cousin Abby, Mrs. Bright
        Measurements: 3.5” x 4.5” - 3.5” x 5.75”
      - "Eliza": [New York, NY], undated, circa 1830s; cuid3492 (Box 91, Folder 5)
        Sent From: “Eliza,” [Possibly Cousin Eliza Gardiner from unidentified location, possibly New York, NY]
        Measurements: 3.5” x 4.5”
      - Fosdick, Mary Ann: [New York, NY], 1815 February 2; cuid3493 (Box 91, Folder 6)
        Addressed To: [Mary Catherine L’Hommedieu Gardiner, mother of Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        Sent From: “Mary Ann Fosdick,” [Unidentified Location, Possibly New York, NY]
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social; Captain Sweet; Cousin Eliza; Hartford, CT; Mr. Fiske
      - Gardiner, Samuel Smith: Shelter Island, NY, 1838 August 31; 1843 May 21; 1844 September 30; 1849 December 19; 1850 January 14; 1853 March 11 & December 21; cuid3494 (Box 91, Folder 7)
        7 Letters, 2 Envelope Fragments, 1 Envelope with Indentation, Notation & Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary L’H [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], ℅ Miss Anne [Charlotte] Lynch [Botta], Providence, RI”; “Samuel Smith Gardiner, Esq., William N. Dyckman Office, No. 69 Cedar Street, New York, NY,” “Greenport Post Office, Shelter Island, Suffolk County, NY”
        Sent From: “M.G.H., Cambridge, MA,” "Albany, NY," [Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]; “Samuel Smith Gardiner, Shelter Island, NY,” “Newark, DE,” [Father of Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social / Travel; Benjamin Nicoll; Boston, MA; Cambridge, MA; Clarissa & Egbert Dayton; Eliza; Sag Harbor, NY
        Measurements: 4.5” x 5” - 8” x 10”
      - Gardiner, SL: Westchester, NY, 1845 August 19; cuid3495 (Box 91, Folder 8)
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], ℅ Samuel Smith Gardiner, Esq., Greenport Post Office, Long Island,” [NY]
        Sent From: “SLG,” [Possibly S.L. Gardiner, Relative of Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford’s father, Samuel Smith Gardiner]
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA; New York & Shelter Island, NY, 1847 August 19 - 1849 September 27; undated, circa 1840s; cuid3496 (Box 91, Folder 9)
        19 Letters, 14 Envelopes with Indentation, Notation & Postage
        Addressed To: “Mrs. Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner Horsford, ℅ Eben Norton Horsford, Esq., Rumford Professor H.C., Cambridge, MA”
        Sent From: [Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford], “The Abbey Manor,” [Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY]; “℅ [Ruben Bombey], Esq., No. 64 Irving Place, Corner of 18th Street,” [New York, NY], [Sister of Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social; Catherine Nicoll; Miss Havens; Miss Woodbridge; Mrs. Crook
        114 Pages, Bound & Unbound
        Measurements: 3.25” x 4” - 4.75” x 7.5”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Shelter Island, NY, 1847 July 18 - 1848 March 4; undated, circa 1840s; cuid3497 (Box 91, Folder 10)
        10 Letters, 5 Envelopes with Indentation, Notation, Postage & Seals, 3 Envelope Fragments
        Addressed To: “Mrs. Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner Horsford, ℅ Eben Norton Horsford, Esq. Rumford Professor H.C., Cambridge, MA”
        Sent From: [Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford], “The Abbey Manor,” [Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY], [Sister of Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social / Travel; Chancellor Rent; George Fox; “Julia & the President,” [Julia Gardiner Tyler & President John Tyler]; Seals with glitter, possibly gold-leafing
      - Lane, Francis Eliza Gardiner: Shelter Island, NY, 1848 February 15; cuid3498 (Box 91, Folder 11)
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford]”
        Sent From: “Fanny, The Abbey Manor," [Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY], [Frances Eliza Gardiner Lane, Sister of Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        Measurements: 4” x 5.75”
      - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine: Shelter Island, NY, 1841 October 14; cuid3499 (Box 91, Folder 12)
        Addressed To: “Mrs. Bright, Miss Mary L. [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner, Miss Phoebe D. [Dayton] Gardiner [Horsford], No. 68 North Pearl Street, Albany,” [NY]
        Sent From: [Mary Catherine L'Hommedieu, Grandmother of Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford, Daughter of Ezra L’Hommedieu & Mary Catherine Havens]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Religion / Social; Mrs. Benjamin Nicoll; Uncle David Gardiner
      - "Lizzie": Albany & Geneva, NY, 1844 January 20 - November 23; 1846 November 20; cuid3500 (Box 91, Folder 13)
        6 Letters, 1 Envelope with Indentation, Notation, Postage & Seals
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary L.H. [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner, ℅ Samuel Smith Gardiner, Esq., The Abbey Manor, [Sylvester Manor], Greenport Post Office, Shelter Island, Long Island,” [NY]
        Sent From: “Lizzie”
        Measurements: 5” x 2.25” - 8” x 10”
      - "Lucie": [New York, NY], undated, circa 1840s; cuid3501 (Box 91, Folder 14)
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary L.H. [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], Present”
        Sent From: “Lucie,” [Unidentified Location, Possibly Albany or New York, NY]
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social / Religion
        Measurements: 3.75” x 4.75”
      - "Maria": Boston, MA, 1841 December 21; 1843 January 1; [no year] August 31; undated, circa 1840s; cuid3502 (Box 91, Folder 15)
        4 Letters with Notation & Postage & Seals
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary L. [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], ℅ A. Crittenton, Esq., Albany Female Academy, Albany, NY,” “Miss Mary & Phoebe [Dayton] Gardiner [Horsford],” “℅ Colonel Gardiner, Shelter Island, Shelter Island, Suffolk County, NY”
        Sent From: “Maria”
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social; Augustus Davison, Edward Whiting; Mary Parker; Mrs. Bright
      - “Mary B”: New York, NY, undated; cuid3503 (Box 91, Folder 16)
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary LH [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], ℅ Mrs. Bright, No. 68 Pearl Street, Albany, NY,” “Albany Female Academy,” [Albany, NY]
        Sent From: “Mary B., Stuyvesant,” [New York, NY]
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social; “The Wish” Poem
        Measurements: 4” x 6.25” - 8” x 10”
      - Meys, AM: [New York, NY], [no year] January 22, circa 1840s; cuid3504 (Box 91, Folder 17)
        Addressed To: “Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford]”
        Sent From: “A.M. Meys,” or [A.M. Meiss], [Unidentified Location, Possibly Albany or New York, NY]
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Religion / Social; Eliza, Mrs. Bright
      - National Birth Night Assembly: Washington, D.C., 1845 February 24; cuid3505 (Box 91, Folder 18)
        Addressed To: "Miss Gardiner," [Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        Sent From: "National Birth Night Assembly, Carusi's Saloon, Washington, D.C."
        Measurements: 5.5" x 9"
      - Sutherland, Gracie: Geneva, NY, 1844 September 6; cuid3506 (Box 91, Folder 19)
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary L.H. [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], ℅ Samuel Smith Gardiner, Esq., Greenport Post Office, Shelter Island, Long Island,” [NY]
        Sent From: “Gracie Sutherland”
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social; Helen Hawkins; Mrs. Bright
        Measurements: 6.75” x 8.25”
      - Tyler, Julia Gardiner: [East Hampton, NY], [no year] September 30; undated, circa 1840s; cuid3507 (Box 91, Folder 20)
        Addressed To: “My dear Cousin,” “Miss Mary L.H. [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], No. 68 North Pearl Street, Albany,” [NY], “Shelter Island, NY”
        Sent From: “Cousin Julia,” [Julia Gardiner Tyler from unidentified location, possibly Gardiners Island, East Hampton, NY]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Margaret Robinson; Maria Hawkins; Mrs. Bright
        Measurements: 4” x 5” - 8” x 10”
      - Van Wyck, Pierre C: Princeton, NJ, 1815 June 25; cuid3508 (Box 91, Folder 21)
        Addressed To: “Misses Gardiner,” [Frances Eliza Gardiner Lane, Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford]
        Sent From: “Pierre C. Van Wyck,” [Possibly Pierre Cortlandt Van Wyck, American lawyer & politician from NY]
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social; “Annual Commencement Ball Of The College Of New Jersey”
      - Waterman, Magdalene: Penn Yan, NY, 1846 August 4; undated, circa 1840s; cuid3509 (Box 91, Folder 22)
        2 Letters, 1 Envelope with Indentation, Notation & Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], Shelter Island, NY”
        Sent From: “Magdalene Waterman”
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social; Albany Female Academy Trustees; Miss Benham in Albany, NY; Marie Bacon at Watertown; Miss Robinson, Miss McCormick, Miss Hall
        Measurements: 4” x 2.5” - 4.25” x 7.25”
      - Woodbridge, Abby Dwight: Albany, NY, 1841 July 17 - 1844 December 23; cuid3510 (Box 91, Folder 23)
        12 Letters, 1 Envelope with Indentation, Notation, Postage & Seals
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], ℅ Samuel Smith Gardiner, Lafayette Place, New York,” [NY], “Shelter Island, Suffolk County, NY”
        Sent From: “A.D.W.,” “A.D. Woodbridge, 21 Franklin Street,” [Abby / Abigail Dwight Woodbridge],“Albany / Spencertown / Stockbridge, NY,” [Cousin of Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social / Travel; Miss Fowler, Mrs. Bright
        41 Pages, Bound & Unbound
        Measurements: 4.5” x 1.75” - 7.75” x 9.75”
      - Woodbridge, Abby Dwight: Albany, NY, 1845 January 6 - 1847 March 18; cuid3511 (Box 91, Folder 24)
        13 Letters, 5 Envelopes with Indentation, Notation & Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], Corner of 18th Street, Irving Place, New York,” [NY], “The Abbey Manor [Sylvester Manor], Greenport Post Office, Shelter Island, Suffolk County, NY,” “Washington D.C. ℅ Mr. Robinson”
        Sent From: “A.D.W.,” “A.D. Woodbridge," [Abby / Abigail Dwight Woodbridge], "Albany / Brooklyn / Spencertown / Stockbridge,” [NY], [Cousin of Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social / Travel; Mr. Robinson of Buffalo, NY, brother of cousin Helen; Mrs. Bright
        60 Pages, Bound & Unbound
        Measurements: 4” x 2.5” - 7.75” x 9.75”
      - Woodbridge, Abby Dwight: Albany, NY, 1846 November 7; undated, circa 1840s; cuid3512 (Box 91, Folder 25)
        35 Letters, 4 Envelopes with Indentation, Notation & Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], Brooklyn, NY,” “℅ Alexander Gardiner, Esq., New York,” [NY],” “℅ Samuel Smith Gardiner, Esq., The Abbey Manor [Sylvester Manor], Greenport Post Office, Shelter Island, Suffolk County, NY,” "Washington, D.C."
        Sent From: “A.D.W.,” “A.D. Woodbridge," [Abby / Abigail Dwight Woodbridge], "Albany / Brooklyn / Stockbridge,” [NY], [Cousin of Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social / Travel; Henry James
        127 Pages, Bound & Unbound
        Measurements: 3.5” x 4” - 7.75” x 9.75”
      - Woodbridge, Abby Dwight: Albany, NY, undated, circa 1840s; cuid3513 (Box 91, Folder 26)
        18 Letters, 2 Envelopes with Indentation, Notation & Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Mary [L’Hommedieu] Gardiner [Horsford], No. 68 North Pearl Street,” [Albany, NY], “The Abbey Manor [Sylvester Manor], Greenport Post Office, Shelter Island, Suffolk County, NY”
        Sent From: “A.D.W.,” “A.D. Woodbridge," [Abby / Abigail Dwight Woodbridge], "Albany / Brooklyn, NY,” [Cousin of Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford]
        57 Pages, Bound & Unbound
        Measurements: 4.25” x 2.25” - 7” x 8.75”
    - Subseries 2: Manuscripts and Printed Materials
      Record Group IV, Series B, Subseries 2:
      are arranged alphabetically by record type and provided title. In the case that a record includes more than one date expression, the listing will begin with its earliest. If a record is physically undated, approximate ranges are provided. These records are noted "undated" and followed by a "circa" estimate determined by the range represented in the same series
      - Diary: "The Abbey Manor", 1848 August 25 - 30; cuid3514 (Box 91, Folder 27)
      - Event Program: "Young Men's Association, 66th Anniversary of American Independence", 1842 July 4; cuid3515 (Box 91, Folder 28)
      - Manuscript: "Indian Legends and Other Poems", undated, circa 1840s; cuid3516 (Box 91, Folder 29)
      - Manuscript / Printing Proofs: "Indian Legends and Other Poems", undated, circa 1840s; cuid3517 (Box 91, Folder 30)
      - Manuscript / Printing Proofs: "Indian Legends and Other Poems", undated, circa 1840s; cuid3518 (Box 91, Folder 31)
      - [Poetry by Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford], 1840 - 1849; cuid3519 (Box 91, Folder 32)
      - [Poetry by Others], 1847 February 14; undated, circa 1840s; cuid3520 (Box 91, Folder 33)
      - The English Version Of The Polyglott Bible With Marginal Readings. De Silver, Jr. & Thomas: Philadelphia, PA. 1834. [With Inscription & Marginalia], cuid3521 (Box 91, Folder 34)
      - Waterbury, Jared Bell. Advice to a Young Christian on the Importance of Aiming at an Elevated Standard of Piety. G&C & H. Carvill: New York, NY. 1830., cuid3522
        Separated Material
        This published work was removed to Fales Special Collections and is available for use.
        The Bobcat call number is as follows: BV4520 .W3 1830b Box Non-circulating.
  - Series C: Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford
    Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford was born on August 13, 1826 to Samuel Smith Gardiner and Mary Catherine L’Hommedieu Gardiner. With sister Mary Gardiner Horsford, Phoebe was privately tutored until she attended Albany Female Academy and met Eben Norton Horsford. Phoebe was an accomplished seamstress and married Eben Norton Horsford on July 22, 1857, after his first wife, her sister Mary, passed away just two years earlier. Eben and Phoebe produced one daughter, “Nellie” (Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford). Phoebe passed away October 8, 1900 in Cambridge, Massachusetts.
    Record Group IV, Series C, pertains to Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford’s personal and public life in the form of three series arranged by record type. Subseries 1: Correspondence includes communication in the form of invitations, letters, and telegrams. Subseries 2: Financial and Legal consists of account books, appraisals, home and life insurance documentation, inventories, tax records, and three drafts of Phoebe’s will. Subseries 3: Notebooks and Printed Materials features private papers in the form ephemera, manuscripts, and notation, with collected and original poetry and genealogical writing.
    Subseries 1 is arranged alphabetically by company or individual surname, while the materials of Subseries 2 and Subseries 3 are arranged alphabetically by record type[s] and provided title. In the case that a record includes more than one date expression, the listing will begin with its earliest. If a record is physically undated, approximate ranges are provided. These records are noted "undated" and followed by a "circa" estimate determined by the range represented in the same series.
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      Record Group IV, Series C, Subseries 1, pertains to Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford’s personal and public life in the form of communication with her family, friends, and an assortment of aristocracy. Genres range from contact in the form of announcements, calling / visiting cards, financial records in the form of bills, checks, and receipts, invitations, illustrations, letters, notation, manuscripts of travel writing, ornate lace valentines featuring bird, floral, and hair designs, original and collected poetry, photographs, postcards, and telegrams; and original and reproductions of printed ephemera in the form of advertisements, newsprint clippings, and pamphlets.
      Series D, Subseries 1, is dominated by records that capture Phoebe’s personal life, featuring over 361 letters (2,065 pages) just from her immediate family. Subjects range from current community events, local and international travel, to private family business and Shelter Island estate management, public and shared social experiences, to testimonies of religious faith. This subseries features communication with the New England elite of the period including Anne Charlotte Lynch Botta, Caroline Lane Jebb, Edith Longfellow Dana and Richard Henry Dana III, Elizabeth Aspinwall Pulsifer Wyman and Morrill Wyman, Frederick Albion Ober, Helen Hunt Jackson, Henry James, Sr., Henry Van Brunt, James Russell Lowell, Julia Gardiner Tyler, Sara Chapman Thorp Bull, and Sarah Orne Jewett. In addition, these contents include genealogical information from Fannie Washington Finch (Frances Louisa Augustus Washington Finch), great-great niece of the first president of the United States, George Washington.
      Boston, Massachusetts; Personal papers.; Pamphlets.; Letters (correspondence); Personal correspondence.; Advertisements.; Postcards.; Visiting cards.; Fliers (printed matter); Portrait Prints, British.; Cabinet photographs.; Poetry.; Black-and-white photographs.; Financial records; Eulogies.; New York, NY; Family |x Religious life.; Shelter Island (N.Y.); Newport, Rhode Island; Cambridge (Mass.); Travelogs.; Accounts.; Telegrams.; Manuscripts; Drawings; Clippings (information artifacts); Receipts.; Photocopies.; Washington, George, 1732-1799
      - "Alea": [In Transit / At Sea], 1884 June 20; cuid3523 (Box 92, Folder 1)
        Addressed To: “Mrs. Horsford,” [Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford: Cambridge, MA]
        Sent From: “Alea, R.M.S. Germanic,” [Unidentified Location]
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Shelter Island, NY
      - American Loan & Trust Company: Boston, MA, 1886 September 6; cuid3524 (Box 92, Folder 2)
        1 Postcard, 1 Envelope with Postage
        Addressed To: “Phoebe [Dayton Gardiner] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA / Shelter Island, NY”
        Sent From: “Actuary N.W. Jordan, American Loan & Trust Company, 55 Congress Street, Boston, MA”
        In Reference To: Business / Financial / Professional; Advertisement for interest rates
      - Arnold, Newton Darling (ND): Providence, RI, 1896 November 21 - 1898 December 20; cuid3525 (Box 92, Folder 3)
        6 Letters, 6 Envelopes with Postage, 1 Calling / Visiting Card
        Addressed To: “Mr. [N.D. / Newton Darling] Arnold,” “Phoebe [Dayton Gardiner] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA”
        Sent From: “Mrs. Eben Norton Horsford,” “N.D. [Newton Darling] Arnold”
        In Reference To: Business / Friendship / Personal / Professional / Social; 2 printed copies of correspondence referring to Rumford Chemical Works Thanksgiving & Christmas celebrations for employees
        Measurements: 4.25” x 3” - 5” x 8”
      - Bartleu, George A: New Castle, NH, 1884 July 14 & 27; August 8; cuid3526 (Box 92, Folder 4)
        3 Letters, 3 Envelopes with Postage
        Addressed To: “Mrs. Phoebe [Dayton Gardiner] Horsford, Shelter Island, NY”
        Sent From: “George A. Bartleu, The Wentworth, New Castle, NH”
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Cambridge, MA
      - Bateman, Charles H: Shelter Island, NY, 1895 August 21, September 3, October 22, November 3; cuid3527 (Box 92, Folder 5)
        4 Letters, 1 Financial Record with Notation
        Addressed To: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford,” “Mrs. [Eben Norton] Horsford,” [Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford]
        Sent From: “C.H. Bateman”